Matthew Sawatzky Full Stack Web Developer

matthewrsawatzky@gmail.com • (204) 226-3534 • LinkedIn • GitHub • Portfolio

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Developer experienced in both front and back-end technologies. Skilled in UI/UX design to create user friendly, clean and visually pleasing websites. Educated in cybersecurity to ensure data privacy and website security. Experience developing in teams to meet project deliverables. Effective communicator in both the workplace and client environments. Problem-solving skills built to effectively solve bugs and errors in code.

EDUCATION

Red River College Polytechnic

August 2023 – September 2024

Diploma, Full Stack Web Development

Winnipeg, MB

- Received a comprehensive education specializing in full stack web development covering all aspects of the web development industry, with a focus on programming, agile development, object-oriented design, IT solutions, business requirements & systems, project management and communications.
- Project-based education imitating real world project deliverables.
- Collaborated on team-based projects, applying Agile methodologies to simulate real-world development environments.
- Completed projects involving API development, data management, and responsive web design.

SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Java, PHP, Python, Ruby

Database Management: Skilled in SQL to create and maintain well-structured data tables.

Cybersecurity: Educated in implementing validation, authorization, and encryption to ensure websites and code meet the highest standards of web security.

Version Control: Experienced in Git for agile and collaborative workflows, including branching, merging and resolving conflicts effectively in team-based environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BIA Benefits

August 2024 – December 2024

Internship

- 4-Month internship developing for a nationwide business improvement area benefits company offering deals and services to a consumer base of businesses and employees.
- Worked in a development team to meet client set deliverables and deadlines.
- Facilitated and lead client meetings receiving feedback and changing website code in JavaScript and React.
- Responsible for securing API endpoints, validating form elements, maintaining and ensuring a visually appealing and cohesive website design and debugging both my own code and others.

Blue Sky Fitness

September 2024 – Present

Freelance

- Created a TypeScript landing page from scratch for a local fitness studio.
- Collaborated closely with the client to meet their specific wants and requirements.
- Developed a responsive and user-friendly fitness website to provide users with a comprehensive idea of what the studio offers.
- Implemented React and Tailwind CSS to create a cohesive and visually appealing website experience.